<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Porfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Porfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a little bit about my background.
I was born and raised in Maracaibo, Venezuela. Now as a 23-yr old American dual citizen, I am grateful to have lived and experienced two different worlds and two completely different life experiences. I miss my home country deeply, but America opened its doors to me and my family as Venezuelan immigrants and it has become my 2nd home. Although it has not been easy to be away from family, I have learned that the best gift that came from moving is meeting new people that can change your life for the best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/2020/05/14/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/14/about/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a little bit about my background.
I was born and raised in Maracaibo, Venezuela. Now as a 23-yr old American dual citizen, I am grateful to have lived and experienced two different worlds and two completely different life experiences. I miss my home country deeply, but America opened its doors to me and my family as Venezuelan immigrants and it has become my 2nd home. Although it has not been easy to be away from family, I have learned that the best gift that came from moving is meeting new people that can change your life for the best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Blog Post</title>
      <link>/blog/python-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/python-blog-post/</guid>
      <description> This is a brief exchange between Python and R code.
# Python code list=[&amp;#39;10&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;27&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;4&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;23&amp;#39;] list[2] ## &amp;#39;4&amp;#39; # R code library(reticulate) py$list ## [1] &amp;quot;10&amp;quot; &amp;quot;27&amp;quot; &amp;quot;4&amp;quot; &amp;quot;23&amp;quot; list &amp;lt;- py$list print(list[2]) ## [1] &amp;quot;27&amp;quot; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Blog Post</title>
      <link>/2020/05/13/python-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/13/python-blog-post/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>###Intro
library(tidyverse) library(Ecdat) library(dplyr) doc &amp;lt;- DoctorContacts doc &amp;lt;- select(DoctorContacts, -c(lc, idp, lpi, fmde, physlim, linc, lfam, sex, black)) doc &amp;lt;- doc[-(361:20186),] #The dataset I obtained comes from the source https://vincentarelbundock.github.io/Rdatasets/datasets.html. It observes the number of outpatient visits to a medical doctor across different variables. “Health” indicates the health of an individual, poor, fair, good, and excellent. The variable “ndisease” indicates the number of chronic diseases an individual has, “educdec” shows the years of schooling of the head of the household, “child” represents whether that person is over 18 (1=True, 0=False), ages of the individuals, and lastly “mdu” is the number of outpation visits to a medical doctor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>project1</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Intro For Project 1, I have chosen to split a single dataset in two. The original dataset is called “insurance” obtained from the website Kaggle (source: https://www.kaggle.com/mirichoi0218/insurance). The data is obtained from a random sample of individuals in the U.S. It contains 3 categorical variables: sex, smoker, and region, and 4 numerical variables: age, bmi, children, and charges. I split the dataset into two separate datasets and re-joined them again using dplyr functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>Life Objective To be the most proficient I can be and to continue learning in any setting. Gaining experience is a limitless virtue that I want to achieve throughout my career endlessly.
 Skills • Bilingual: fully proficient in English and Spanish • Proficient in RStudio programming • Proficient in Python programming • Spanish tutor for local high school students in my hometown, Katy, TX • Extensive knowledge on Windows and macOS, can operate either operating system at the fullest • Detail-oriented, leader, intuitive, flexible and communicative • Team-leadership and team bonding skills obtained from group interactions throughout high school and college • Fast learner, can adapt to new surroundings at ease and establish connections quickly</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>